Whoa.
That him?
Yeah.
How you know?
'Cause I drug him around
with my horse till he told me.
Looks like
somebody ran away from home.
Somebody with a big mouth.
I-I'll go back, talk to him.
Ain't gonna matter none.
Alright.
Let's get on with it, shall we?
I-I got money!
- Ain't enough.
- How do you know?
- It's never enough.
- Wait, wait!
I-I got something.
I-I got something real valuable.
Show me.
Where was that? They...
Here we go.
I think I... Here it is.
Did you check his pockets?
This is your own
damn fault, then, ain't it?
And that goes for you, too.
No. God!
Close. But it ain't God
you got all riled up.
It's worse.
It's said that a great sickness
took hold of the country
that summer of 1849...
taking Christian and heathen
with equal justice...
and killing horse, cow,
and anything with four legs
almost as swiftly
as the outlaw John Glanton
and his murderous gang,
who were slaughterin' their way
across the Western territories
in search of
valuable scalp bounties.
But this is not
his story of evil.
There was another.
No!
That's all I got.
We've been through this,
Miss Abraham.
Worthington.
You know that well as the next.
You signed the papers.
Yes.
Miss Worthington.
Like I was saying,
we've been through this.
And ain't no one gonna
escort you nowhere right now.
And that's fact.
On account of me being a Slate?
Slate. Injun. Two-headed
Mexican. Don't matter a shake.
It ain't safe
out there right now.
And you know that. No
matter how much silver you got.
What about you?
Surely this town
can survive five days
without your steady hand on
the tiller of justice, Deputy.
Acting Sheriff,
Miss Worthington.
You know that well as the next.
Has been since Sheriff Buford
went missin'.
She needs help.
Well, I'll see to it
Doc Steelbender comes
to take a look at her
as soon as he is fully conscious
and in possession
of his faculties.
Ain't that right, Doc?
Yeah.
Now, you know that's not the
kind of help I'm talking about.
I need to get
her to Ross Corner.
How about it,
Doc? Little paid excursion?
Look after Miss Worthington?
The man
can't look after himself.
And you can't travel alone.
I'm not alone.
And how is she with a pistol?
Now, I suggest you take
that little girl of yours home.
Before she causes a stir.
You know you're not
supposed to be in town with her.
It's a superstitious
lot we have here.
And you remember what happened
the last time they got riled up.
Thank you for
your time... Acting Sheriff.
The food.
Do you for five or six days.
And you could fill the bladders
out back where the pump is.
As long as
she doesn't touch anything.
Much appreciated.
I also need to get this
telegraph to Ross Corner.
Alert the preacher that
I'm on my way
and in need of his assistance.
You are in touch with
Ross Corner,
are you not, Mr. Grayson?
I'll see what I can do.
Oh. Miss Atwater.
Uh, pleased to see you.
I wish I could say the same.
Yes, well, we were just in town
picking up a few supplies and...
Then you come
alone. Or not at all.
That was the agreement.
Yes, ma'am.
You bring that... thing...
into town one more time,
and I'll have
you both strung up.
On charges, that is.
How's the curing business, Doc?
Not as good as
the dying business.
Well, at least the sickness
seems to have abated.
It's a shame it took so many.
What's in Ross Corner?
Why don't you ask her?
I don't reckon I'm that curious.
Is that all there is?
Tell me, Bender.
What's it like to be a doctor
who can't save a life?
I'll let you know next
time you find yourself sick.
Would you like to recite us
a little scripture, Edward?
Oh, I surely would, Miss Sarah,
but you know I...
I ain't much of a reciter.
I'm more of a listener.
But y-you know what I heard the
other day outside the general?
I heard this... this...
this Tubman woman been...
She's been building a railroad
under the ground for... for years.
All this time,
they's been worried
about the slaves
escaping topside,
and she just goes
and builds a-a railroad
under the ground like that
sure as sunrise.
Is that so?
It certainly is so.
Because the two gents
playing checkers
out on the porch said it was.
And I-I believe
they was both speaking truth.
Although,
I have to admit that the...
the gent with the whiskers
did seem to be
using this conversation
as a... as
a distraction mechanism,
which made the other gent miss
several jumps and a king-me.
But I-I believed
his words nonetheless.
And y-you know
what else I heard?
How about we save
the rest for morning?
It's getting a little late.
I have some things to prepare.
Yes, ma'am.
Come on, flapjack.
Let's get you in your jammies
so your mama can tuck you in
all snug as a bug.
Which is a funny expression
if you ask me,
because I-I have
never seen a snug bug.
Especially not in a rug, which
is the part of the expression
that I seem to have left off.
Alright.
I need you to get
a good night's sleep
because we're gonna go
on a long trip
and I need
you to be brave, okay?
I need you to be a big girl.
How about a smile for mama?
Papa?
I don't feel right, Papa!
Fell off your horse in
the middle of town again, Doc.
Speaking in tongues
like some kind of lunatic.
Yeah. Won't... Won't happen again.
No, it certainly will not.
Oh. Miss Atwater. What a...
What a pleasant surprise.
Mr. Steelbender.
Doctor.
Hm. Questionable.
Tell me. Why are you here?
Not this jail. We all
know you are an inebriate.
Why here? This town?
I don't know.
I suppose after the army,
I wanted a clean start.
Tired of guns
and killing people.
Seems you've succeeded
in killing people
without any guns,
Mr. Steelbender.
Doctor.
Hm.
The town has decided
it's time you moved along.
The whole town decided that
or is it just you?
I'm calling your note.
I ain't behind.
You are now.
As of this minute.
Unless you can pay in full?
I thought not.
One week.
See to it that the good... doctor
has departed by then.
Deputy.
Acting Sheriff.
Hm.
She can't do that.
I'm afraid she can.
Well, I ain't digging up my
whole family for that old witch.
She ain't the law.
She's the bank. Even better.
Now, promise me you won't
go doing something stupid.
- I can't.
- Why?
Where you off to?
To do something stupid.
I'm not a very good shot,
but I reckon at this range
I don't have to be.
I'd rather not test
that theory. It's Bender.
Well, what do you want?
To take you up on your offer.
We can leave at sunrise,
but I expect half up front.
Sunrise it is!
Come on! We gotta
go! Let's get a move on!
Gotcha!
What are you doing here,
you scoundrel?!
- Get off me!
- Don't you lie to me.
'Cause I saw you sneaking
around here last night
like some kind of
nefarious character!
I-I even recognize
your voice on account
- that I'm a good listener.
- Get off!
I bet you didn't know
there's a little drum
in each one of our ears.
Get off me, you idiot!
What did you call me?
- Stop it! Please!
- I called you an idiot!
No, he... he don't mean no harm.
He works the farm.
This... This here is...
Edward. Edward T. Yacht.
Pleased to meet you. I...
Edward, um,
that here's Dr. Steelbender.
He's agreed to escort me
on a little journey,
so I might be gone for a while.
Oh. G-Gone? Gone where?
Just keep doing
what you're doing. Alright?
And I need you to put
these documents in a safe place.
They mean nobody
can take our ranch away.
Well, why... why would anyone try
as hotheaded a thing
as that, Miss Sarah?
This here ranch, it's yours,
s-sure as sunrise.
Mr. Worthington, I mean, h-he
gave it to you on his deathbed.
God rest his soul.
And now I'm bestowing it to you.
In case I don't come back.
You understand?
Um...
I'm not certain
I do, Miss Sarah.
Take good care of the ranch.
And if anybody
asks any questions,
show 'em these here papers.
I-I'm still
struggling with something
you said a couple phrases back.
I-I could have sworn you said,
uh, "In case I don't come back."
And... And that... that just must be
me misreading
the verbal situation.
'Cause y-you always
come back, Miss Sarah.
S-Sure as sunrise.
Remember what I said, Edward.
Sweetpea,
let's get a move on, now!
Mr. Worthington said
for me to look after you!
What kind of name
is that? Edward Yacht?
Name he came with.
The name he came with?
Mr. Worthington, uh, took him in
after his wife passed.
Found him out living
on the streets with the pigs.
Asked him
his name. Edward goes...
"People call me idiot."
Without raising an eyebrow,
Mr. Worthington says,
"Well, that's
a right proud name,
but I don't much care
for nicknames like Eddie,
so from here on out,
your name's gonna be
Edward Yacht, not Eddie Yacht."
Huh.
Mr. Worthington was a good man.
He could be.
Is that why you took his name?
Man frees his slaves,
you take his name.
That's the custom.
You know where we're headed?
Mm-hmm.
S-Somewhat.
I beg pardon.
Just you don't strike me as much
of a frontiersman.
I'm not much of
a doctor, neither.
Good girl.
You stay where
I can see you. Alright?
So?
So what?
So we gonna talk about it?
There ain't
nothing to talk about.
I just never got to offer
my condolences is all.
I mean, her taking
her life like that.
Lord knows my Joseph
was no saint, but your wife...
Your wife was a good woman.
Yeah. She was.
Until she wasn't.
What's so
important in Ross Corner?
Come on, now, Doctor.
Everyone within a hundred miles
knows about my little girl.
And you think the doctor there
is gonna help?
No.
If I thought a doctor
could help,
I would have taken her to you.
Going to see Preacher Ross.
What, and he's gonna cure her?
He gonna save her.
He's got the touch.
She's got the devil.
A powerful one. Make no mistake.
You sound like
those crackpots in town.
She's a carrier is all.
You're smart to keep
those hand covers on her.
Keep the sickness contained.
But she's no more
wicked than you or me.
You don't believe
in the devil, Doctor?
I wish I did. Then maybe I'd
believe in the good Lord, too.
Just tall tales and fiction
designed to get us through
the night.
No better than a campfire.
Hmm.
Toss your steel this way,
and things won't get a mess.
Gibson!
Took you long enough.
Button it.
Alright. Let's get you over
to your... your proper owner.
Ain't his nothing.
I'm a free woman.
Well.
Well, you hear that, Gibson?
She's a... She's a free woman.
Free as a feather.
Well, I reckon you're free...
you're free to go, then.
Ain't that right?
Didn't think so.
She's a quiet one.
What's wrong with you, little
bird? Cat got your tongue?
Oh, they wanna stand.
Okay. Stand. Come
on. Stand. Stand up!
Okay.
Toss your food bag.
Toss it to him.
Now the water.
Now...
Take off them clothes.
Seems your ears are workin'.
All of it.
Alright.
We're gonna take your things.
But we're gonna leave your
horses so you can get on home.
'Cause that's what
a mannered person does.
But to make sure
you ain't gonna follow,
we're gonna take
this little bird with us.
No!
I always
wanted me a little girl.
I'm very womanly in that way.
Don't.
You wait a day.
We're gonna let her loose
by the ravine
about two miles west of here.
But iffin you come
lookin' for her before,
let's just say...
there ain't gonna
be much left to find.
And that is
a promise, bullet to Bible.
You call yourself a woman?
Maybe I do.
Maybe I don't.
Perhaps you'd
prefer iffin I was a man.
Is that it?
Go on. Show me.
Go ahead.
Go on.
Please.
Calm yourself.
We ain't gonna
take her to the ravine.
- We're gonna drop her in it.
- No.
Gotcha!
God damn, fuck.
Go on, git!
It's gonna be
tender for a while.
Turn over.
That's the best I can do
without any water.
She take everything?
Yeah.
We'll find some on the way.
We're turning back.
What you mean?
Ain't no quitting
over a couple thieves.
They weren't thieves. Thieves
wouldn't leave those horses.
They were after your girl.
Why? Why...
Why would they be after her?
I don't know.
Maybe you should ask him.
Think he's alright?
It was his choice to follow.
I just want
to make sure he's okay.
He had the wind
knocked out of him is all.
Which, of course,
don't mean he's okay.
You know what else I heard?!
A few years back,
the United States government
laid claim to a place at the top
of the world called Ant-Artrica!
And that... that entire country
is made of ice!
Imagine that?
A whole country made of ice?
I-I say we bring some of
that ice down here right now,
and then we'd all
have us plenty of water.
That's what I say.
'Cause, you know, you know, you
know, ice is just frozen water!
Maybe you should
save your breath, Edward!
Don't you worry, Miss Sarah!
I-I can peddle this here bone
shaker all day iffin I have to,
and it seems I do at the moment.
Cannot ride a horse
if the heavens depended on it.
A-As I mentioned, in truth,
there weren't a horse
on the farm that weren't...
- Yah!
- Lying dead in the dirt.
You go right on ahead,
Doc Steelbender!
I-I can keep up as
long as I can see you!
I'm pretty good
at following tracks.
She needs water.
Well, we ain't gonna find none
standing idle.
I might climb that butte
and take a look around.
You wait here for the simpleton.
Edward.
Right. Mr. Yacht.
Annie?
Think it was
the Indians did that?
I don't think nothin'.
All's I know is we need to
find a different way around.
Hm.
Won't make
it another day in this heat.
I'm aware of the situation.
Weren't your fault, you know.
I used to blame myself,
thinking there was something I
did to drive him into her arms,
but... they was just moths
to a flame is what I think.
I'd rather not
discuss the matter.
You think that's gonna
make like it didn't happen?
What, put a feed bag
over your head? Well, it did.
Weren't your fault and
weren't mine. Was his and hers.
Well, they surely paid for it,
didn't they?
I'm sorry.
She couldn't look me in the eye
once the shame set in.
I had to pry this out of
her fingers
when I found her by the river.
I can still smell that gunpowder
in her hair.
Hm.
Ain't no running from it, is it?
I think that's why I left that
old noose up all these years.
My way of atoning.
To the lynch mob?
To you.
We... You best
sleep. I'll keep a look.
That's it.
There we are.
That's all I got, I'm afraid.
Yeah?
I just want to take a look
inside your mouth.
Can you open up
your mouth for me?
I'm not gonna hurt ya.
I'll tell you what. If
you let me take a little peek...
I'll...
I'll let you hold
this for a little while.
Used to belong to
someone very special to me.
Can I take a look
inside your mouth?
It's not gonna be hurt.
There we go.
Doctor!
Found a way around!
Get up!
Hey! Y...
You ever hear about t-the game
they play up in New York City?!
In their pajamas?
Seems a bunch of grown men
stand around in... in a field
whacking a ball with a stick.
Just running
around like schoolchildren.
Call themselves
the... the Knickerbockers.
I examined her, you know.
Told you. Ain't
that kind of sickness.
Well, I didn't see any sign
of the devil, neither.
Now you're just
trying to get a rise.
People come from all over,
pay money to watch 'em do it.
It's like... like
going to the circus
to see a... see
a two-headed goat.
All I know is...
some preacher hocus-pocus
ain't gonna make
a damn bit of difference.
I heard he healed a bullet hole
just by touching it.
- Tall tales and fiction.
- Now, if you have a...
If a two-headed goat
could whack a ball with a stick,
t-that'd be
something I'd pay to see.
Especially if it was...
w-wearing... pajamas...
Edward!
He's gonna be alright, ain't he?
Here.
Breathe this in.
Breathe it in. Breathe it in.
You alright?
Sorry, Doc.
I do tend to go
on a bit, don't I?
Excuse us.
We're looking for some water.
Well, now, that's something
we have plenty of.
Stanton,
get these folks some water.
Can't you see
they're about to drop?
Easy, now. Not so fast.
There, now. Little
girl's got the hang of it.
We appreciate your hospitality.
Oh, there's plenty of food there
for everyone...
but not till it's
cooked and ready.
Got enough troubles without
everyone getting food-sick.
What's wrong with them?
Well...
Emma there, my niece...
just seen too much life,
the best I can describe it.
Stanton...
Well, he's my eldest, and...
I just got tired of
looking at him, I suppose.
You know, he got
the sickness a while back
and just keeps
getting worse and worse.
Don't know how
much longer he's got,
but judging by the liquid
oozing out of him,
I'd say... maybe a week or two.
Ain't that right, Stanton?
Well...
now that we're all acquainted...
If you don't mind,
I'd like you to put your weapons
over there near the barrel.
That's where we keep ours
when they're not in use.
Uh, I might hang on to mine,
if you don't mind.
Got some
sentiment attached to that?
It's the last
thing my wife ever held.
Well, we can't take that away
from a man, now, can we?
If you don't mind,
Stanton will hold onto his, too.
Got some
sentiment there as well.
Ain't that right, Stanton?
Well, look at us.
All civilized and such.
Name's Maggie.
Now, I'd ask yours,
but I have a feeling I wouldn't
get a straight answer.
Much appreciated.
What brings
you out this way, ma'am?
Well, them horses.
Till they died and we ate 'em.
You have to forgive an old woman
a piece of humor.
There ain't been
much to talk to out here.
No, we come out west for gold.
Well, I-I know all about
the... the rush for gold.
I-I heard in... in February
a whole boatload of people
pulled right up on...
on the sands of Frisco
and dropped to all fours
and just started digging
before they even had a proper
meal or washed their armpits.
Yes. Gold fever. Mm-hmm.
We caught it, as well.
Started out with 12 wagons,
a proper family.
Now it's just us.
Got plenty of water, but...
That there is last of the food.
What happened?
Well, I'm not so sure
where to start on that. I...
We survived two onslaughts.
The first one...
most of the men was killed.
Just outright butchered.
Being scalped is probably
as close to being raped
as a man will ever get.
Just having the flesh ripped off
the top of your head like that?
Them Injuns is an inhuman
set of creatures, you ask me.
The second attack was worse.
Mostly because it was inflicted
on us by white men.
Descended on us
like a posse from hell...
just whoopin' and hollerin'.
Worse than any Injun.
Leader had black eyes.
Like a doll.
They raped all the women.
Killed all the horses.
Maybe they raped the horses,
too. Wouldn't surprise me.
But they left us alone
on account of Stanton.
It seems like the one thing
that everybody respects
is the sickness.
And then...
They just vanished.
They took all the scalps
they could collect
and disappeared like vapor.
Never knew who they were.
Maybe they was ghosts.
Just gonna relieve myself.
I think the good Lord sent
you to us. That's what I think.
And I think that
with some food in your belly
and a good night's sleep...
we're gonna be
like one big family.
That's what I think.
Here you go, darlin'.
Bless you.
And there's some for you.
- Thank you.
- And you come on with me. Ooh!
Oh. No, no.
That's fine. She's, uh...
Now, you're not
gonna deny an old woman
the small
pleasure of holding a child.
My goodness. There you go.
Alright.
Now let us give thanks.
Papa?
Amen.
Don't eat that.
Leave it.
- What's wrong?
- Nothing's wrong.
We're just leaving is all.
It appears that your friend
ain't too fond of my cookin'.
I don't blame him.
Emma ain't too fond
of it, neither. Poor girl.
There was no choice!
It was God's truth!
Gather up the girl,
and let's be on our way.
No, you sit down
right where you are!
And I'd appreciate you
not pointing your gun at my son.
Now, the fact of the matter is,
you may get a shot off
before he does
in his current state of affairs,
but not before I twist
this little rabbit's neck.
And I can assure you...
my state of
affairs is quite acute.
Intelligent decision.
We may make it out west after
all. Ain't that right, Stanton?
In the morning...
we're gonna hitch up our horses.
And who knows,
maybe your huntin' luck
is better than ours,
and we won't have to resort
to any... unfortunate measures.
Now, you best be grateful.
A less refined
group of individuals
might simply choose
to leave you behind to...
Leave you behind to...
Mama?
Mama!
What'd you do?
What'd you do to her?!
Mama!
Ooh.
Pardon the intrusion.
I suggest we depart immediately.
Come back!
You sheep fucker... Ohh!
We call this "irony."
I thought it was a buzzard.
Thank you again for
allowing me to accompany you.
Oh. We're the ones
should be grateful.
Is it, uh, "Chief"?
William. William Shakespeare.
- Is that so?
- It is.
Why have you been tracking us,
Mr. Shakespeare?
I needed traveling companions,
preferably white.
Safer that way.
What happened to your people?
My people vanquished me.
I thought when Injuns vanquish
you, they do it with a blade.
You are a suspicious man.
Only when it comes to Injuns.
I assure you,
it's not the "Injuns"
you should be concerned about.
Oh, my God.
Oh. Uh, forgive me.
It's quite alright, ma'am.
The Quechan are, for
the most part, peaceful farmers.
When they took me in, they were
dazzled by my verbal skills.
Thought I could protect them.
But they were wrong.
There was no negotiating
with the White Riders.
Only running.
And after the slaughter,
my people banished me.
Said I could not return
unless I bring stronger magic.
W-What kind of magic?
Bakotahl.
What's a... Bakotahl?
More of a "who," lad.
Bakotahl is the evil half
of the great
Quechan creator Kokomaht.
His... dark twin, if you will.
Legend has it
that Bakotahl was born blind,
and this angered him,
so he unleashed
a great evil onto the world
and then
disappeared into hiding.
The Quechan believe that
Bakotahl still walks amongst us
in disguise, and, if captured,
his spirit can be harnessed
as a powerful magic.
A living talisman, if you will.
Well, perhaps that
magic talisman of yours
can find us some water.
Wait here.
I don't trust him.
You don't trust nobody.
You know, the first time
I-I saw an Injun, I was...
Shut up.
Whoo! Come on, flapjack!
Last one in's
a rotten road apple!
Gonna have to be
quicker than that.
Ohh!
Ah. These will make a fine stew.
No shepherd's pie, mind you.
You're probably wondering about
my history, Dr. Steelbender.
Don't really concern me.
Don't come across many Indians
who speak proper English,
I'll wager.
I've not come across
many English who speak
proper English, neither.
Wit.
You would do
well in London, sir.
Is that where you're from?
My village
was raided by trappers
back when I was a boy.
French. Horrible people.
Never bathe,
far as I could tell.
They rounded us up
and sold us to the British.
"Red savages," they called us.
I ended up in the custody of
a naval officer named Wilkinson.
Went to work in the manor.
His wife was so kind to me.
On Sundays, she used to
teach me the king's tongue.
"If you're going to live
with us, you're gonna be
a proper gentleman,"
she used to say.
Even named me
after her favorite author.
Well, like I said,
it don't really concern me.
I-I didn't...
I didn't mean nothing.
I-I swear. I...
Y-You know that, right?
I'd tear my
heart out for your ma.
Would just tear...
tear it right out, I would.
I suggest
you keep your sidearm dry.
I've seen a wet pistol
blow a man's hand clean off.
You don't much care
for my kind, do you, Doctor?
Well, on the contrary.
If it weren't for Injuns,
I wouldn't be able to put food
on the table.
There's not a lot of money
in doctorin',
but there's certainly money
in making chains
to lock up Injuns.
Bit of a blacksmith,
are you, Doctor?
When I have to be.
There. See? Now we're having
a right proper conversation.
There's an old Quechan saying...
"Even the stiffest reed
will eventually
bend to the wind."
We have a saying, too.
"Some steel don't bend."
Everything alright, Edward?
I don't believe
I've ever seen you this quiet.
I'm just tired
is all, Miss Sarah.
Well, here. Have some stew.
Our friend made it special.
Thank you, ma'am.
Alright. Eat up. Get some rest.
We'll be at
Ross Corner soon enough.
Here you are.
- Oh. Thank you.
- Mm-hmm.
It's pretty good.
Needs a little something.
Uh-huh.
Never claimed to be a lady. Hm.
I don't... I don't drink.
Well, aren't you full of
surprises, Dr. Steelbender?
I promised my daughter.
And "Bender" is fine.
Alright. Bender.
Where's Chief William?
I don't know. He's out there
somewhere taking watch.
Still don't trust him?
Nope.
Well, he hasn't killed us yet.
So that's something.
Mm-hmm.
I'll wager you believe me now.
About what?
The old woman. My girl.
I believe people get sick.
And judging by her companions,
I'd say she was carrying for
a while.
You got it all
figured out, don't you?
Well... Well, all except him.
Why are you so
attached to that halfwit?
I got my reasons.
Uh-huh.
And don't
you call him no halfwit.
I'm just sayin' a fact.
He's sweet on you, you know.
Don't be silly.
Well, a man has eyes...
What make
you such an expert on people?
'Cause I'm a doctor.
I have a certificate
and everything.
Mm-hmm. Mm-kay.
You're such an expert on people,
why you ain't got
more of them around?
Ah.
I forgot myself. I'm sorry.
It don't matter.
It's, uh...
It's hard to say.
Edward...
Was right after
they hanged my Joseph.
Sheriff Buford came callin'.
Asked who was responsible
for such a crime.
Like he ain't know.
Said we should pray together.
That God would see justice done.
So we knelt.
Prayed in silence.
Next thing
I know, I'm on all fours.
With the good sheriff behind me
serving up a dose
of God's justice.
He would have killed me after.
If it weren't for Edward.
We buried him in the foothills.
Edward and me.
The sheriff's disappearance
became a mystery, and...
Nine months later,
had me that baby girl.
White as chalk on bone.
Townsfolk whispered, but they...
They pretty much let us be.
Until people and animals
started dying, and...
the truth about my little girl
started spreading.
No more truth than the lies
coming out of Ross Corner.
What is the matter with you?
Why'd you even come with us?!
I told you. I needed the money.
Oh, you needed the money?
You needed the money?
Then here. Take it!
I relieve you of your contract.
I understand trying all you can
to save what's yours.
That, I couldn't do.
I'd tear my heart out...
for her.
You...
You know I...
I would.
Oh, my God. Oh, my...
He said it right to our face.
She's his goddamn talisman!
Hey! Wake up! Wake up! Wake up!
We gotta go.
We gotta go. He took her.
- He took her.
- Who? Who?
- We... We gotta find her.
- Edward?!
- No! Come on. Come on.
- No!
He's gone. Let's go.
It was them
bounty hunters, most likely.
'Course.
Unless it was another tribe.
- 'Course.
- Least he got his due.
The chief.
Not like the boy
did that to himself.
'Course.
Come on, sweetpea.
Let's get you all washed up.
Come on. Come to Mama.
Good girl.
Ohh...
Don't go too far.
Just taking
her down to the river.
No!
Stop! She's just a girl!
Has to be.
Sarah!
And we both know it.
Sarah! Stop!
Stop! Aah!
Sarah!
That's far enough, now.
You just turn right back around.
Take that unholy
creature with you.
- Please.
- "Please" don't work here.
If you noticed...
I didn't use the word.
Now, you best retreat.
And don't let her touch nothin'
on the way out!
Sheriff!
Alright. That's enough
posturin' for one day.
Can't you see this fella's
in need of some hospitality?
Welcome! I'm Ross.
Preacher Ross or Doc Ross.
Whichever you prefer.
It makes no difference
in the eyes of the Lord.
And I answer to both.
- I'm...
- I know who you are, Doctor.
And I know why you've come.
Let us help you.
We can carry this weight.
Fine. Yes.
As you will. Alright.
Now, you all know this child.
And you've
heard all the stories.
But this girl is
not to be feared.
In truth, she's to be praised.
For she carries in her all
that is wicked in this world,
and she soaked
it in like a sponge.
So, yes, this girl
should be praised,
for what she has contained...
is the devil himself.
And come tomorrow in our church,
I shall release
her from this evil...
through the righteous power
these hands have been granted!
You all know this power!
Do it now.
Cure her or kill her!
Makes no difference.
Preacher said tomorrow!
My predilection is today.
It's alright.
We're a family here, so...
let's put it to a vote.
All in favor of
Willard's predilection here?
Huh?
No?
Then it's settled!
Tomorrow it is.
Now I want
you all to go and pray,
for I need every ounce of faith
come morning.
Come, Doctor. You'll
be comfortable in our home.
She'll just be over here,
you know? Right in eyesight.
Here.
Your mama fixed, uh...
fixed him for ya.
She loves you very much,
no matter what.
There we are. Almost done.
There you go.
Here. Go ahead.
No.
What?
No bad habits, Doctor?
I got plenty of those.
That's right. Um...
Perhaps then instead
you might prefer...
a little of this?
You see...
that is the wonder
of modern invention.
Right here.
You ask it questions,
and it answers.
I believe that one
day everyone will have
one of these
devices in their home.
And who knows... maybe even
we'll walk around with them,
tapping out messages.
I don't know
what your play is, Ross.
All I know is I made a promise
to that young girl's mother.
Oh. I-I'm very sorry. I...
Yes. These are
simple people, and I...
But I don't
often have an occasion
to converse with someone
of intellect and reason.
As you can see, my confidant,
he's not much on idle
conversation.
He had his tongue cut out
when he was a boy.
There is such
evil in this world.
I'm not
particularly one for evil.
Hmm.
Sure.
This girl...
she simply has a sickness.
Just as your poor daughter did.
Right? Am I right?
That's right.
I will tell you, Doctor.
And others
here will attest to this.
Miracles do happen.
And I have seen them.
These hands...
have been part of them.
I'm sure you've
heard my stories.
Just as I heard of yours.
Tall tales and fictions.
Yeah.
Faith is the currency of fools.
That's your belief.
Am I right, Doctor?
Well, what if you're wrong?
What if there is
evil in this world?
I'm not saying bad men.
I am saying true evil.
Evil of the purest form.
Well, doesn't that also mean
there is good?
Well, if there's shadow,
there must be a light.
And if there is a hell,
then there must be a heaven.
And if you can accept this,
your loved ones,
your dear daughter...
she's not dead and gone.
She's here.
She's living
eternal. And she's at peace.
Can you allow yourself
just that flicker of hope,
you know,
for the briefest moment?
Could you also allow yourself
to believe, to hope,
to even...
even pray for evil?
I promise you.
Tomorrow
we shall free that girl.
And in the aftermath...
you shall believe...
anew.
On that...
you have my word.
Bullet to Bible.
Tomorrow.
"Bullet to Bible"?
Where's the girl?
She's sleeping.
No. No, no. It don't...
It don't have to be...
Yeah,
I'm afraid it does, Doctor.
I-I tried to keep it
from coming to this.
I sent Miss White
here to keep that girl
from ever
showing up on my doorstep.
Well, we all know
how that turned out, don't we?
- She's just a girl.
- Yeah.
I've got a whole town
full of people that believes
that she's the devil.
They're fools.
On that we both agree.
But how's it gonna look
when I wave my hands
over that little thing...
and then a week later,
a flock of
sheep just drop dead...
a child gets ill...
schoolmarms just start
choking up blood?
The good
people of this community
will think me a charlatan
and string me up.
There is one thing
that I do believe, Doctor.
The ignorant.
You never fear
the ignorant getting smart.
You fear
the ignorant getting scared.
Please. We'll disappear.
Oh, oh, no.
It's too late for that.
"Cure her or kill her."
You... You heard it yourself.
Since I can't cure her...
I got this.
You evil son of a bitch.
Come, Doctor.
We both know there's no evil.
There's just very bad men.
I say we put a bullet in him.
The desert does
the killing, Miss White.
We merely set things in motion.
Well, look who it is.
You should be asleep, child.
It's late. Here.
Come on. Get up on here.
There we go.
You know...
Why don't
I read you a story, huh?
You like stories, don't you? Hm?
Yeah.
My father, he used to read
to me when I couldn't sleep.
You know?
Ah, back...
That was a long, long time ago.
Yes.
Back when things were simpler.
Hm? Oh!
Now, look. Now,
that is one of my favorites.
Alright. Here we go.
Ain't your fault.
Annie.
You did the best you could.
Well, I couldn't...
I couldn't save you.
You tried.
But I lost you.
And I lost your mother.
Everyone.
What was it you always told me?
About being a Steelbender?
That some steel don't bend.
So break it.
What the hell is that?
The sheriff wants to know
if we're in the need of more
reliable security.
Tell that fuckin' gimp
he's a fuckin' gimp.
Yeah...
You're alive.
Hardly.
How did you find me?
You're an easy horse to track.
Well...
My sweetpea. Where is she?
Is she alright?
She... She will be.
Oh, God forgive me.
Uh, I-I don't know
what came over me.
That wasn't you.
Wasn't it?
I'm the one
should be in that pit.
Stop it. That's idiot talk.
We... Come on.
I-I can't.
I can't. I can't. Not...
- She's your daughter.
- I can't!
You go.
Please go.
Don't.
Throw it over here.
Well, well, well!
Look what the cat...
You gonna shoot me, Doctor?
I'm not a killer.
I think Miss White
would beg to differ.
The sheriff's on his way.
We'll be gone. Wake up.
She's already gone, Doctor.
Wake up.
Wake up. Wake up.
Wake...
Come on.
Hey. Here. Breathe this in.
Yeah. See? There...
There was a glimmer of hope.
Quiet!
T-There's no shame in it.
I saw it in your eyes.
- Please. Please.
- Clear as day.
I said quiet!
Look.
Doctor.
It's another miracle.
You stay right there.
Yes. They move.
Who are you?
Oh, I've been so
many different people.
I kind of lose track.
Who are you?
Oh.
That's right. You're a poor man.
You don't have
any family, do you?
Don't you come any closer.
And that...
that is too much
for one soul to bear.
Is there a comfort...
possible for you now?
Is there?
No comfort?
Ah!
It's a shame
that it has to come to this.
Once word gets out
about what you've done here,
taking that little girl's life
like you did,
they're going to
have to take yours...
and they're
gonna put this evil to rest.
There you go.
No. There's no need to beg.
No. No begging.
There's some things
I've grown immune to.
So have I.
Ho-ho!
You're gonna
need that chair now.
Oh! God damn!
Come on. Come on.
Oh, no.
No.
Ross!
I don't feel right, Papa.
No! No! No!
Some say
the ghost of Preacher Ross
still walks these hills.
Others say he wriggled away,
like a worm cut into pieces.
But I couldn't tell you,
and I was witness.
And in truth, perhaps we need
people like him in this world.
The horror they inflict.
For their very existence,
be it truly evil or not,
may be the only hope
that tethers us
to proof of the divine.